Appala Srinivas Tanakala

Visakhapatnam, Andhra Pradesh, India | +91 88974 15303 | tasrinivass@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/srinivasta | Kaggle: kaggle.com/srinivasta

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/srinivas-t-a-557637119

Summary:

20+ years in financial services (equity trading, risk management, branch management, sales)

3+ years as Data Scientist: ML, AI, data analytics, Kaggle contributor

Skilled in Python, SQL, Power BI, Tableau, data visualization, dashboarding, predictive modeling

Strong leadership, team & client relationship management, and strategic planning

Education:

Bachelor of Commerce - Andhra University

Certifications:

AI/ML for Geodata Analysis, IIRS/ISRO (Sep 2024)

Data Analyst / Business Analyst, ExcelR (Mar 2022)

Al Masterclass, ExcelR (Apr 2022)

Machine Learning, Tata Steel (Apr 2020)

Digital Marketing, Accenture (Apr 2020)

Electric Vehicle Design, Pantechelearning (Jul 2022)

Technical Skills:

Languages: Python, SQL, Excel, Power BI

Tools: pandas, NumPy, matplotlib, seaborn, scikit-learn, Streamlit

Domains: Financial Analytics, Stock Market Prediction, Real Estate Data

Professional Experience:

Data Scientist (Freelance)

May 2022 - Present | Remote

Built AI/ML models for stock, crypto, insurance datasets, and real estate analysis

Developed Streamlit apps: stock predictor, chatbot, video summarizer, portfolio tracker

Awarded Bronze Medals in Kaggle competitions

Senior Manager – Sales SVMS Constructions

Aug 2019 - May 2022

Managed product launches, customer engagement, and sales pipeline for real estate projects

Data Processing Analyst IDA Automation Pvt. Ltd. (Client: Fidelity US) | Jul 2017 - Aug 2019

Cleaned and analyzed title insurance data, delivered insights and dashboards

Branch Manager - Aditya Birla Money Ltd.

Jul 2005 - Aug 2015

Led ₹4 Cr daily turnover branch, managed sales team & product distribution (Equity, Commodities, Insurance)

Earlier Roles:

ICICI Bank Officer, DP Executive at AMB Financial, Trading Operator at Steel City Securities (2001–2005)

Honors & Awards

Bronze Medal, Santa 2024 – The Perplexity Permutation Puzzle (Kaggle)

Bronze Medal, Predict Podcast Listening Time Challenge (Kaggle)

Plus multiple other recognitions and hackathon participations on Kaggle and AI/ML platforms